Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 4 J. A. Fishman Course Outlines and Notes 1935-1993
  - Subseries A Courses Given
    - Health/Health Care: Course Reading Material 4-5 by weekly sessions (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Course Reading Material 6-8 by weekly sessions (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Course Reading Material 9-10 by weekly sessions (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 11 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 11 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 11 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 1 Introduction, Some Basic Concepts, Mind Body/Placebo Effects (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2 "Treaditional" approaches (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 2-3 "Treaditional" approaches, Contact between indigenous and modern western medicines (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 3 Contact between indigenous and modern western medicines (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 4-5 the "Sick Role" and the Illness experience, Doctor-Patient interaction (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 4-5 the "Sick Role" and the Illness experience, Doctor-Patient interaction (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 4-5 the "Sick Role" and the Illness experience, Doctor-Patient interaction (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 5 the Doctor-Patient interaction (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 6 Modern Alternatie Medicines (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews, cross cultural comparison (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews, cross cultural comparison (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews, cross cultural comparison (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews, cross cultural comparison (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 7-8-9 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 8 Blacks, Hispanics, Jews, cross cultural comparison (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 9-9A southeast Asians (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 10 Resligion as medicine (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 10-10A Shamanism (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 10-11 Religion as Medicine, Medicine as Religion (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 10-11 Religion as Medicine, Medicine as Religion (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12 How Language is Used (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12 How Language is Used (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12 How Language is Used (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 12-13 How Language is Used, Which Language is Used (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 13-14 Which Language is Used, Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 14 Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 14 Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 14 Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 14 Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Health/Health Care: Week 14 Review/Summary (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B Summer Institutes
    - Sociolinguistic Seminar (Indiana University, Bloomington) Summer 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sociolinguistic Seminar (Indiana University, Bloomington) (Cont'd.) Summer 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sociology of Language, Bilingualism, Language Planning (Philippine Normal College, The Philippines) April 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sociology of Bilingual Education (Harvard University) Summer 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sociolinguistic Foundations of Bilingual Ed (Columbia University,NY) Summer 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sociolinguistic Foundations of Bilingual Ed (Columbia University, NY) (Cont'd. 1) Summer 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sociolinguistic Foundations of Bilingual Ed (Columbia University, NY) (Cont'd. 2) Summer 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Language Policy, Planning and Political Processes, Sociology of Bilingual Education (University of Hawaii, Honolulu) Summer 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sociolinguistic Foundations of Bilingual Education (Columbia University, NY) Summer 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Sociolinguistics (University of Illinois) Summer 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Sociology of Bilingual Education (Adelphi University, NY) Summer 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sociology of Language (University of San Francisco, CA) Summer 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (University of New Mexico, Albuqurque) Summer 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (University of New Mexico, Albuqurque) (Cont'd.) Summer 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 1)Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 2) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 3) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 4) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 5) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Final Reports (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 6) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Entertainment (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 7) Summer 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 8) Summer 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 9) Summer 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 10) Summer 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 11) Summer 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 12) Summer 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 13) Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: The Students (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 14)Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Outline/Bibliography (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 15)Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Student Applications (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 16)Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Student Applications (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 17)Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities: Publicity (Yeshiva University, NY) (Cont'd. 18)Summer 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA)Summer 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 1)Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 2) Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 3) Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 4) Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 5) Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 6) Summer 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 7) Summer 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 8) Summer 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Language Shift Among American Ethnolinguistic Minorities (Stanford University, CA) (Cont'd. 9) Summer 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Future of Ethnic Languages (Monash University, Austrailia) Summer 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Issues in the Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (Stanford University) Summer 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Issues in the Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (Stanford University) (Cont'd. 1) Summer 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Issues in the Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (Stanford University) (Cont'd. 2) Summer 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Issues in the Sociology of Language: Language & Ethnicity (Stanford University) (Cont'd. 3) Summer 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C Courses Taken
    - SOTSIYALE VISNSHAFT / GESHIKTE / YIDISH / POLITISHE EKONOMIYE / LITERATUR (Yiddish Courses Taken in Yiddish High School)1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Zoology (Parmenter) 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - English Composition 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - English (Weygandt), Logic (Adams ?), Spanish (Doyle) 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - HEKHERE KURSN (Yiddish Courses Taken After Graduating From Yiddish High School) 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Psychology (Freeman, Barnett) 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sociology (Crawford, Pollack), Political Science (Harter), Economics (Nettinger) 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - History - Medieval (Dobson, Masterson), History - England (La Monte) 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - History - Spanish ( Wardropper, Romero-Navarro, Regalado), English Literature (Kitchen) 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - History (Watts) 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - GRUNDVERK FUN DER YIDISHER LITERATUR (Max Weinreich) 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - YIDISHE LITERATUR TVSHN DI TSVEY VELT-MILKHOMES (Max Weinreich) 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Psychology (Shaw) Fall 1947 (or Spring 1948) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - History - Russia (Kirchner), Political Science - Latin American Government (Cale) 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Education (Mullin) 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Education (Russ) 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Education (Russ) (Cont'd.) 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - History - Jews in America (JAF Notes in Yiddish) (Salo Baron) 1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - YIDISHE FOLKSLITERATUR UN FOLKLOR (Max Weinreich) 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - YIDISHER FOLKLOR (Y. L. Kan Klub baym Yivo) 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker)1948 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker) (Cont'd. 1)1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker) (Cont'd. 2)1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker) (Cont'd. 3)1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker) (Cont'd. 4)1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - StatisticsI & II (Helen Walker) (Cont'd. 5)1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Personality Development and Mental Health (Hobbs)1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Philosophy of Education (Dean Minnick)1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Talmudic Judaism (Salo Baron)1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Educational Psychology (Gates & Watson)1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Education (Henderson)1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Experimental Psychology of Motivation (Irwin)1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Social Psychology (Preston)1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Orientation in Educational Research and Planning (Lorge, Symonds, Walker, etc.)1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Doctoral Seminar: Educational Psychology (in preparation for JAF doctoral thesis) (Irving Lorge)1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Education (in preparation for JAF doctoral thesis) (Irving Lorge)1950 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Psychoanalysis and Learning Theory1950 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Language and Remedial Work in Reading (Arthur Gates)1950 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Case Studies of Counseling (Virginia Axline)1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Basic Concepts in Counseling and Psychotherapy (M. Eiserer)1951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Russian1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Grammatical Structure (Bill Labov)1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Introduction to Linguistics (Charles Ferguson)1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Phonology (Lotz-Garcia)1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - SSRC Summer Seminar - Learning and the Educational Process1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - SSRC Summer Seminar - Learning and the Educational Process (Cont'd.)1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - SSRC Summer Seminar (JAF notes on Chomsky's review of Skinner's Verbal Behavior)1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - SSRC Summer Seminar: Child Language (Charles Ferguson)1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - SSRC Child Language (John Howard)1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - SSRC Summer Seminar (Wally Lambert)1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Hausa (Edgar Gregerson)1965-1966, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hausa (Edgar Gregerson) (Cont'd. 1)1965-1966, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Hausa (Edgar Gregerson) (Cont'd. 2)1965-1966, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hausa (Edgar Gregerson) (Cont'd. 3)1965-1966, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series 5 Book Reviews, Prefaces and Forwards 1950s-1990s
  This series contains drafts, revised versions, and the final published item. Subseries A contains the prefaces and forwards; Subseries B contains the book reviews. The series is bilingual (English/Yiddish).
  - Subseries A Prefaces and Forwards
    - Prefaces - Henry Trueda's Book; Bilingual Education in Friesland; Culture & Language Learning; In Appreciation of the Thesaurus (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Prefaces - Language Contact - Language Conflict; Language Reform - History & Future; Sociolinguistic Perspective on National Languages; Social Issue of International Migration Review (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Forwards - Albar Pena's Book; Raising Children Bilingual: The Pre School Years; Bilingual Education & Language Maintenance...; The Ethnic Process; Bilingualism & Language Contact in the Borderlands (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Forwards - Amenagement et Politique De La Langue; Bilingual Education in a Bi-national School; Language Maintenance...; Sociolinguistics: A Sociological Critique (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B Book Reviews
    - The Alchemy of English; Bilingual Education: History, Politics...; Bilingualism & Bilingual Education: A Comparative Study; Blessings, Curses, Hopes & Fears... (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Case Studies in Bilingual Education, Coping with Cultural & Racial Diversity...; The Education of Linguistic Minorities...; Every Goy's Guide to Common Jewish Expressions; Exotic Readings in Cultural Texts (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Filipino Bilingual...; GROYSER VERTERBUKH FUN DER YIDISHER SPRAKH...; A Host of Tongues; Implications of the Ethnic Revival in Modern Industrial Society; Intelligence & Cultural Environment, etc. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kommentierte Bibliographie zun Slavischen Soziolinguistik; Language & Poverty: Perspectives on a Theme; Language & Social Psychology; Languages and Their Territories (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Language, Ethnicity and the Schools; Language Loyalty in South Africa; Language, Meaning and Maturity; Language, Society, Identity; Language: The Socio-Cultural Context (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Legal and Criminal Psychology; Linguistic Imperialism; Linguistic Minorities, Policies and Pluralism; Literacy and the Language Barrier; The Meaning of Yiddish (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minority Education: From Shame to Struggle; Mirror of Language...; The New Bilingualism...; DER OYSTER FUN YIDISHN FOLKLOR; Problems in Applied Educational Sociolinguistics (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Process of Communication: An Introduction to Theory & Practice; The Role of the Culture-Group Affiliation of the Judge in theThurstone Attitude Scale Construction (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Social Life of Language; The Sociolinguistics of Society; The Sociometry Reader; Speaking of Diversity...; The Spread of English; The Stigma of Names; TOGBUKH FUN VILNER GETO (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - DVOPROSY SOCIOLOGII JAZYKA; Welsh Fever: Welsh Activities in the United States & Canada Today; Why Jewish Immigrants and Their Children Did So Well in City College; Yiddish: A Survey and a Grammar (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series 6 Interviews 1965-1991
  This series contains copies of interviews conducted with Dr. Fishman.
  - Interviews 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interviews (Cont'd.) 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 7 Publicity and Travel Arrangements 1947-1992
  This series pertains to travel arrangements and publicity for conferences, meetings, and lectures and contains itineraries, reservations, tickets, lists of expenses, descriptive brochures, clippings, publications, and some photographs. It is arranged by date.
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements (Cont'd.) 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements (Cont'd.) 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements (Cont'd. 1) 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements (Cont'd. 2) 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/Travel Arrangements 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series 8 Centers for Advanced Studies 1963-1983
  This series pertains to Dr. Fishman's time at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, CA), the East-West Center (University of Hawaii, Honolulu), the Institute for Advanced Study (Princeton, NJ), the Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study (Wassenaar, Netherlands), and the Israel Institute for Advanced Studies (Hebrew University, Jerusalem). Materials include information on the center and documents pertaining to Fishman's work while in residence.
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, CA) 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - East - West Center (University of Hawaii, Honolulu) 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - East - West Center (University of Hawaii, Honolulu) (Cont'd.) 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Institute for Advanced Study (Princeton, NJ) 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study (Wassenaar, The Netherlands) August-January 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Israel Institute for Advanced Studies (Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel) February-June 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 9 Tributes and Celebrations Honoring J. A. Fishman 1986-1991
  This series pertains to Dr. Fishman's honorary degree from Vrije Universiteit, Brussels, 1986; tributes on his 60th and 65th birthdays; and his retirement celebration. Organized by date.
  - JAF Honorary Degree (Vrije Universiteit, Brussel) May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - JAF Honorary Degree (Vrije Universiteit, Brussel) (Cont'd.) May 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Tribute to JAF in Honor of His 60th Birthday 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Tribute to JAF in Honor of His 60th Birthday (Cont'd. 1) 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Tribute to JAF in Honor of His 60th Birthday (Cont'd. 2) 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - JAF Retirement Celebration at FGS/YU May 18, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sol on the Horizon - A Tribute to JAF on his 65th Birthday July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sol on the Horizon - A Tribute to JAF on his 65th Birthday (Cont'd. 1) July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sol on the Horizon - A Tribute to JAF on his 65th Birthday (Cont'd. 2) July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sol on the Horizon - A Tribute to JAF on his 65th Birthday (Cont'd. 3) July 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series 10 J. A. Fishman Notes on Work of Colleagues
  This series contains work by others (typescript articles, photocopied chapters, etc.) with Dr. Fishman's handwritten annotations and comments.
  - JAF Notes on Work of Colleagues (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - JAF Notes on Work of Colleagues (Cont'd. 1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - JAF Notes on Work of Colleagues (Cont'd. 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series 11 Recommendations 160-1990s
  Access to this series is restricted. No container list will be included in this guide.